Guide to the University Marshal records, 1825-2005 RG0043
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Programs and addresses, 1826-2005; RG0043 Series 2; 7.5 Linear feet (Box 12, Box 14, Box 4, Box 1, Box 15, Box 3, Box 2, Box 11, Box 9, Box 10, Box 7, Box 8, Box 5, Box 6)
  - Other School addresses--School of Engineering Commencement Address by Dr. Harold Wheeler, 06/01/1905 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Other School addresses--School of Education and Human Development Commencement Address by Thomas Minter, 05/04/1980 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Other School addresses--School of Government and Business Administration Commencement Address by Capt. Grace Hopper, USNR, 05/03/1981 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Other School addresses--School of Public and International Affairs Commencement Address by Elliot Richards, 05/03/1981 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Opening Convocations-programs--GWU opening of academic year, 09/03/1984 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Opening Convocations-programs--GWU opening of academic year, 09/12/1986 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Opening Convocations-programs--GWU opening of academic year, 09/11/1987 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Opening Convocations-programs--GWU opening of academic year, 09/09/1988 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Opening Convocations-programs--GWU opening of academic year, 09/08/1989 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Opening Convocations-programs--GWU opening of academic year, 09/07/1990 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Opening Convocations-programs--GWU opening of academic year, 09/06/1991 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Opening Convocations-programs--GWU opening of academic year, 09/12/2000 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Medical School opening, 09/18/1961 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Medical School opening, 09/16/1963 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Medical School opening, 09/14/1970 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Medical School opening, 09/10/1971 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Medical School opening, 09/08/1997 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - GWU Presidential Inauguration Convocations--programs--President Lewis, 11/07/1923 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - GWU Presidential Inauguration Convocations--programs--President Carroll, 05/03/1961 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - GWU Presidential Inauguration Convocations--programs--Address by U.S. President Kennedy, 05/03/1961 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - GWU Presidential Inauguration Convocations--programs--President Trachtenberg, 04/16/1989 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Honorary Convocations--programs--Mexican President Ortiz Rubio Paschal, 12/28/1929 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Honorary Convocations--programs--King of Siam, 04/30/1931 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Honorary Convocations--programs--President of Ecuador, 11/24/1942 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Honorary Convocations--programs--President of Korea, 08/31/1954 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Honorary Convocations--programs--President of Uruguay, 12/07/1955 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Honorary Convocations--programs--King of Morocco, 11/27/1957 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Honorary Convocations--programs--Lord High Chancellor of Britain and Pres of Amer. Bar Assc., 08/30/1960 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Honorary Convocations--programs--President and Mrs. Ronald Reagan, 03/28/1991 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Honorary Convocations--programs--President of Czech Republic (autographed), 04/22/1993 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Honorary Convocations--programs--President Mubarak of Egypt, 06/29/1999 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Honorary Convocations--programs--President of Costa Rica, 09/05/2000 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Memorial Convocations--programs--Emil Alexander de Schweinitz, 03/05/1904 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Memorial Convocations--programs--President F.D. Roosevelt, 04/13/1945 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Memorial Convocations--programs--President. J.F. Kennedy, 11/27/1963 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Memorial Convocations--programs--GWU President Marvin, 05/01/1969 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Memorial Convocations--programs--Dorothy Betts Marvin, 05/02/1975 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Memorial Convocations--programs--Wood Gray, 06/30/1977 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Memorial Convocations--programs--Reuben Esselstyn Wood, 03/28/1980 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Memorial Convocations--programs--Joseph Louis Metivier, 06/18/1980 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Convocations--programs--GWU 100th Commencement Convocation, 12/15/1924 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Convocations--programs--Special Convocation for Class Day, 06/03/1925 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Convocations--programs--Convocation for German Ambassador, 03/08/1932 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Convocations--programs--Honorary degree to Hanna Knapp Wilbur, 06/04/1935 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Convocations--programs--Constitution Day, 05/18/1938 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Convocations--programs--Honorary degree for Harold Winterbotham and Dan La Cour, 09/01/1939 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Convocations--programs--Special Convocation for Class Night, 05/28/1946 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Convocations--programs--Special Convocation for Class Night, 05/07/1947 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Convocations--programs--Dedication the Hospital, 03/23/1948 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Convocations--programs--Dedication of a Vault for the Future, 06/20/1956 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Convocations--programs--Centennial Convocation of the Law School, 10/12/1965 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Convocations--programs--Special Convocation for M.L. King Jr., 01/26/1992 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Convocations--programs--Special Convocation for M.L. King Jr., 01/21/1999 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Special Convocation--opening addresses--Columbian College opening address by Pres. Staughton, 01/09/1822 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Special Convocation--opening addresses--Medical School opening address by D.W. Prentiss, 10/01/1892 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Special Convocation--opening addresses--Address to Freshman by Pres. Lewis, 09/23/1925 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Special Convocation--opening addresses--Special Convocation address by Pres. Marvin, 12/16/1947 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Special Convocation--opening addresses--Special Law School Centennial Celebration address by William Brennan, 10/01/1965 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Special Convocation--opening addresses--Freshman Convocation address by Justice Clark, 09/12 1966 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--St. John's Church, 06/05/1910 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--Untitled, 06/04/1922 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--Untitled, 05/31/1925 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--Untitled, 06/05/1927 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--New York Avenue Presbyterian Church, 06/10/1928 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--New York Avenue Presbyterian Church, 06/08/1930 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--New York Avenue Presbyterian Church, 06/07/1931 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--New York Avenue Presbyterian Church, 06/12/1932 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--Washington Cathedral, 06/04/1933 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--Washington Cathedral, 06/03/1934 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--Washington Cathedral, 06/02/1935 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--Washington Cathedral, 06/07/1936 (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--Washington Cathedral, 06/06/1937 (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--Washington Cathedral, 06/05/1938 (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--Washington Cathedral, 05/26/1946 (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--Washington Cathedral, 05/25/1947 (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--Washington Cathedral, 05/23/1948 (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--Washington Cathedral, 05/29/1949 (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--Washington Cathedral, 05/28/1950 (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--Washington Cathedral, 05/27/1951 (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--Washington Cathedral, 05/25/1952 (Box 14, Folder 48)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--Washington Cathedral, 06/06/1954 (Box 14, Folder 49)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--Washington Cathedral, 06/05/1955 (Box 14, Folder 50)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--Washington Cathedral, 06/03/1956 (Box 14, Folder 51)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--Washington Cathedral, 06/01/1958 (Box 14, Folder 52)
  - Baccalaureate Services--programs--Washington Cathedral, 06/04/1967 (Box 14, Folder 53)
  - Degrees Conferred--Law School, 03/11/1905 (Box 14, Folder 54)
  - Degrees Conferred--Law School, 03/12/1905 (Box 14, Folder 55)
  - Degrees Conferred--Medical School, 03/14/1905 (Box 14, Folder 56)
  - Degrees Conferred--All graduates, 03/19/1905 (Box 14, Folder 57)
  - Degrees Conferred--All graduates (from hereon), 03/22/1905 (Box 14, Folder 58)
  - Degrees Conferred, 09/30/1966 (Box 14, Folder 59)
    Summer
  - Degrees Conferred, 09/30/1967 (Box 14, Folder 60)
  - Degrees Conferred, 09/30/1968 (Box 14, Folder 61)
  - Degrees Conferred, 09/30/1969 (Box 14, Folder 62)
  - Degrees Conferred, 09/30/1970 (Box 14, Folder 63)
  - Degrees Conferred, 09/30/1971 (Box 14, Folder 64)
  - Degrees Conferred, 09/30/1972 (Box 14, Folder 65)
  - Degrees Conferred, 09/30/1973 (Box 14, Folder 66)
  - Degrees Conferred, 09/30/1974 (Box 14, Folder 67)
  - Degrees Conferred, 09/30/1975 (Box 14, Folder 68)
  - Degrees Conferred, 09/30/1976 (Box 14, Folder 69)
  - Degrees Conferred, 09/30/1977 (Box 14, Folder 70)
  - Degrees Conferred, 09/30/1978 (Box 14, Folder 71)
  - Degrees Conferred, 09/30/1979 (Box 14, Folder 72)
  - Degrees Conferred, 09/30/1981 (Box 14, Folder 73)
  - Degrees Conferred, 09/30/1982 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Degrees Conferred, 09/30/1983 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Degrees Conferred, 09/30/1984 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Degrees Conferred, 09/30/1985 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Degrees Conferred, 09/30/1986 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Degrees Conferred, 09/30/1987 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Degrees Conferred, 09/30/1988 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Office files, 1825-2005; RG0043 Series 3; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series contains schedules, addresses, biographical information, memorandums, lists, newspapers, correspondence, invitations, and forms. They range in date from 1825 to 2005. They concern The George Washington University's commencements and honorary degree holders. One newspaper is in Farsi.
  - Convocations/Commencements Academic costume, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Convocations/Commencements Addresses, 1901-1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Convocations/Commencements Addresses, 1951-1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Convocations/Commencements Addresses Schools Other than CCAS, Law, and Medical, 1974-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Convocations/Commencements Anniversaries GW's 175th, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Announcements, 1970-1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Commencement - 1st, December 15, 1824, 1965 2005 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Commencement, 1825-1919 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Commencement, 1920-1960 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Commencement, 1961-1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Commencement, 1981-1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Commencement, 1987 1999 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Commencement Hooding Ceremonies, 1992 1997 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Commencement Invitations, 1856-1920 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Commencement Invitations, 1921-1940 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Commencement Invitations, 1941 ca.-1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Commencement Tickets, 1918-1944 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Commencement Week Activities, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Commencement Week Activities - Class day, 1899-1925 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Commencement Week Activities Class night, 06/06/1927 --06/10/1940 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Commencement Week Activities, 1859-1935 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Commencement Week Activities, 1936-1980 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Commencement Week Activities, 1981-1995 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Commencement Week Activities, 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Commencement Week Activities, 1995-2005 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Convocations Memorial, 04/13/1945 --03/28/1980 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Convocations Opening Of Academic Year, 1981-2000 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Convocations Special, 1919-2002 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Convocations Special - Convocation for Law School (with letters from Supreme Court Justices), 1949 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Convocations Special--Dedication Of A Vault For The Future, 06/20/1956 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Convocations Special - In Honor Of Prajadhipok, King Of Siam, 04/30/1931 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Convocations Special - Martin Luther King, Jr. Day Medal Awards, 1987-2001 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Convocations Special - Peace Convocation, 04/06/1936 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Convocations Special - School Without Walls 16th Annual Commencement, 06/03/1988 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Convocations Special - Tribute to Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., 01/18/1988 -01/16/1989 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Convocations Winter Convocation, 1905-1987 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1975 -05/25/2003 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Honorary Degrees - Recipients, 1827-2003 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Honorary Degrees - Recipients Biographical information, 1937 -01/24/1986 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Honorary Degrees - Recipients Roh Tae Woo (President of the Republic of Korea), 10/31/1989 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Honorary Degrees - Recipients Shah of Iran, June 1974 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - University Marshal, Office of, 05/30/1971 -12/16/1998 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Commencements and convocations, 1969-1987; RG0043 Series 4; 6 Linear feet
  This series consists of commencement and convocation scripts, honorary degrees and award files, correspondence, and diagrams for university yard and Constituion Hall seating for graduations. There is no arrangement scheme. They range in date from 1969-87, and were transferred to the University Archives in 1998.
  - Speakers and honorary degrees, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - GW awards, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Scripts, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Winter convocation, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Speakers and honorary degrees, 1981-1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - GW awards, 1981-1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Scripts, 1981-1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Spring commencement, 1981-1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Scripts, 1969-1974 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Spring commencement, 1969-1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Winter convocation, 1969-1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Alumni achievement awards, 1969-1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Diagrams - University Yard and Constitution Hall, 1969-1974 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Student marshals, 1969-1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Honorary degrees, 1969-1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Scripts, 1971-1976 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Spring commencement, 1971-1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Winter convocation, 1971-1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Commencement budget, 1971-1976 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Marshal's correspondence, 1971-1976 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - President's correspondence, 1971-1976 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Other ceremonies, 1971-1976 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Sample form letters, 1971-1976 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Ministers, 1971-1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - GW gowns, 1971-1976 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - film of possible commencement, Circa 1980; Series 4 (Box SHARED Box 22, Box 5, Film 1)
    General
    note with reel states "older people in cap and gowns shaking a man's hand, possibly Lloyd Elliot" This note is dated March 2002.
  - Annual Commencement, 1976 May 9; Series 4 (Box SHARED Box 22, Box 5, Cassette 1)
  - Faculty and student letters, 1970-1974 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Diagrams - Yard (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Diagrams Constitution Hall (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
  - Emeritus Professors (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Alumni Achievement (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
  - Honor Societies, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Honorary Degree, 1968-1977 (Box 5, Folder 9-26)
  - Vault of the Future, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Commencements Set of Programs (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Commencement Marshals (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Baccalaureate, June 1968 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Opening Assembly of Medical School, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - National Law Center Commencement, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Student Marshals (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Marshal Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Public Ceremonies, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Winter Convocation, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 36-37)
  - Spring Commencement, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 38-42)
  - Convocation, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 43-44)
  - Scripts, Spring 1971 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Commencement and Convocation Arrangements, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Marshal Correspondence, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 47-49)
  - Scripts, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 50-51)
  - Winter Convocation, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Arrangements: Spring Convocations, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 53)